Xiao Hui, have you eaten enough
小灰啊 饭吃饱了吗
Eat full
吃饱啦
Yeah, and
对 还有
Don't be nervous about the exam
考试啊 千万不能紧张
And
还有
Yeah, ID card
对啊 身份证
Did you bring your admission ticket?
准考证带没带呀
Brought it, brought it
带了 带了
Didn't you ask me everything
您不都问了我
Is it all morning
一早上了吗
Why don't you ask me
您怎么不问问我
Head band or not
脑袋带没带
Did you bring it
那你带没带
brought
带了
Okay, mom
行了 妈
Don't worry
您就放心吧
It's almost time
时间也差不多了
Fear of traffic jams on the road
怕路上堵车
We started early
我们就早点出发了
OK
好 行
Then Grandma, we'll leave first
那奶奶 我们就先走了
Good
好
Don't worry, grandma
放心吧奶奶
OK
好嘞
Good
好
Refuel
加油
Let's go bye bye
走了 拜拜
Bye
拜拜
This is the street of Lao Ma
这是老马街头
The first rice cake shop
第一家米糕店
The first bowl of rice cakes sold
卖出的第一碗米糕
You ate guaranteed high school
你吃了保准高中
The first bowl
第一碗
Mom, do you want to be so exaggerated
妈 你要不要这么夸张
This is your mother
这是你妈妈
Get up at five o'clock in the morning
早上五点钟起床
I bought it when I went out
出门去买的
You must eat the college entrance examination today
今天你高考 必须吃
Good
好
It's a little hot
有点烫
I'll try it too
我也尝尝啊
Eat it and lose all this luck
吃了把这运气都弄掉了
She's the only one who eats it
就她一个人吃
I can't finish it
我吃不完
I want you to eat it too
也要你吃
Dad
爸
I just went in first
我就先进去了
son
儿子
Take a good exam
好好考
To grasp the time
要把握好时间
Be sure to examine the questions carefully
一定要认真审题
Got it
知道了
son
儿子
Refuel
加油
Dad believes in you
爸爸相信你
Got it
知道了
Don't worry, Dad
放心吧 爸
Gone
走了
Examine the questions carefully and don't worry
仔细审题 别着急
Got it, mom
知道了 妈
Uncle Lan
兰叔叔
Dongdong sister-in-law
冬冬 嫂子
Let's go inside quickly
快进去吧
Take the exam well, Dongdong, come on
好好考啊 冬冬 加油
Hello Auntie Ma Yiming Hello Uncle
阿姨好 马一鸣 叔叔好
Get in quickly
快进去
Don't worry, Mom
放心吧 妈
Bye
拜拜
You also come to accompany the exam
你也来陪考啊
Isn't that true
那可不嘛
Yes
是
In this life
人这一生啊
Just this college entrance examination
就这一次高考
No matter how busy you are, you have to come
再忙也得来
That's that
就是 就是
Isn't that Ji-gang
那不是继刚吗
During the exam
考试的时候
Be sure to be calm
一定要沉着
Calmness
冷静
Refuel
加油
How quickly this time flies
这时间过得真是快
Okay, Director Zhang
好的张主任
You said that the hairy boy back then
你说当年的毛头小子
Be the director today
今天做上主任
That's also a style
那也是有模有样的啊
More nervous than the candidates
比考生还紧张呢
We're nervous too
我们也紧张
I'm so nervous
我都紧张死了
Lan Jinghui
兰靖灰
Apprentice Sunny Day
徒弟 晴天
Came so early
那么早就来了
How about it
怎么样
Did you have a good rest last night
昨晚休息好了吗
The spirit is quite good
精气神倒是不错啊
Don't have enough to eat
吃没吃饱
Then you have to eat enough
那必须吃饱了
Are you ready
你准备好了吗
I'm pretty well prepared
我准备相当好啊
Just
就
Lan Jinghui
兰靖灰
Grey Brother
灰哥
Come so early
来这么早
Aren't you the same
你们不也一样吗
Such an important day
这么重要的日子
Of course it has to be earlier
那当然得早一点
Everyone's gathered. Let's go
人都齐了 走吧
Have you seen the monitor
你们见班长了吗
Is it not there
那不在那儿呢吗
monitor
班长
Don't be nervous on sunny days
晴天 别紧张
Play well
好好发挥
Required
必须的
Here's this for you
这个给你
Here's for you
这给你
Thank you
谢谢
Sister Dream
梦姐
Ma Yiming
马一鸣
Ling Dong
凌冬
Refuel
加油
You too
你也是啊
I'll see you at Beijing University
我们京大见
Don't worry
放心吧
The three of us will be fine
我们仨没问题的
Come here quickly on sunny days
晴天 快过来
Rooftop Squad
天台小分队
Come on for college
高考加油
Come
来
Wait a minute
等一下
Meng Yu comes over
梦予 过来
Come
来
Three two one
三 二 一
Come on for college
高考加油
Chen County will win
辰郡必胜
Apprentice Ling Dong
徒弟 凌冬
Both of you have finished the exam
你们俩都考完了
How was the exam
考怎么样
I don't know I didn't think about it
我不知道 我没去想
How can you not think about this
这怎么能不去想呢
How can this not be known
这怎么可能不知道呢
All the exams are finished
考都考完了
What's the use of thinking
想有什么用啊
How about the Lingdong test
凌冬 考怎么样
I don't know
我不知道啊
I didn't think about it either
我也没去想
Not
不是
Why don't you even think about it
为什么都不去想呢
All the exams are finished
考都考完了
What's the use of thinking
想有什么用呢
Then let's go
那走吧
It's on holiday
放假了
Two copies for ten dollars
十块钱两本
Buy one get one free
买一送一
Do you want to buy it
要买吗
Just take a look
随便看看
The book has its own golden house
书中自有黄金屋
Be sure to have a good look
一定要好好看一下
Don't grab it
不要抢
It's okay, it's okay
没事 没事 没事
How's it going
咋样
What do you see
你看呢
We're almost the same
咱俩差不多
I also do this
我也这样
What about those girls
那群女生至于吗
A few old books were grabbed like this
几本旧书就抢成这样
I'm not this old
我这不是旧的吗
You don't understand this
这你就不懂了吧
In Ling Dong's book
人家凌冬的书上
All contaminated is the good luck of Xueba
沾染的都是学霸的好运
It's shallow if you ask me
要我说就是浅薄
Have that time to read the notes for a while
有那个时间看会儿笔记
Is it bad to do your homework
做做功课不好吗
I agree with you
我同意你这观点
Why are you so unlucky
怎么这么倒霉
I'll be in line soon
马上就排到我了
Nothing, nothing
没事 没事
Senior Chen's is still there, let's go
陈学长的还在呢 走
Welcome Welcome Welcome
欢迎 欢迎 欢迎
Don't worry Don't worry
别着急 别着急
Is there Lan Jinghui
有没有兰靖灰
Senior's book
学长的书啊
Lan Jinghui
兰靖灰
Yeah, I heard he was
对啊 听说他可是
Koi fish in our school
我们学校的锦鲤
From the bottom of the grade
从年级倒数第一
The last mock test
最后一次模拟考
Improved by 511 places
进步了五百一十一名
What is this not a koi fish
这不是锦鲤是什么
Is that me the last one talking about
倒数第一说的是我吗
It's not you, it's me
倒数第一不是你是我呀
There's no more
已经没有了
The koi fish is here. Come on, come on, come on
锦鲤在这儿呢 来来来
Over there, over there
那边 那边
Don't worry, don't worry, don't worry
别急 别急 别急
Everyone has it
每个人都有
Upperclassman
学长
Can you sign my dress
能给我衣服签个名吗
I'm going to wear it for the college entrance examination
我要穿着它参加高考
Senior Koi
锦鲤学长
Can I take a picture of your head
我可以拍下你的头吗
I want to make a good jackpot
我想图个好头彩
Senior Koi
锦鲤学长
Can I take a group photo
我可以拍张合照吗
I want to use it as a screensaver for my mobile phone
我想拿来做手机屏保
Senior Koi
锦鲤学长
I want to be a cell phone ringtone
我想当手机铃声
Senior Senior
学长 学长
Senior Senior Senior
学长 学长 学长
He is the first in his grade
他是全年级第一
Look for him, look for him, look for him
找他 找他 找他
Yes, yes, yes
对对对
The same is true for Senior Ling Dong
找凌冬学长也一样
Are these all yours
这些都是你的吗
Sister Dream
梦姐
Xu Mengyu
徐梦予
Wrap it all up for me, I'll take it
都帮我包起来 我要了
Are you sure
你确定啊
Why don't you give it to me
怎么 不肯给我
Not
不是
What do you want these for
你要这些干吗呀
They're all basketball jerseys and stuff
都是些篮球 球衣啥的
You had three times in total
你一共有三次
Call me by my full name
叫过我的全名
The first time I was caught copying
第一次是我抄袭被发现
You came to my house to find me
你来我家找我
The second time was by the lake
第二次是在湖边
When looking at the stars
看星星的时候
The third time was just now
第三次就是刚刚
You remember these
你记这些
Why do you remember so clearly
记得这么清楚干吗
Actually, these things
其实这些东西
In the eyes of others
在别人眼里
Probably just a bunch of junk
可能就是一堆破烂
But in my eyes
但在我眼里
Everything here
这里每一样东西
They were all with you
都是曾经伴随着你
Pursue Dreams
追寻梦想
It's all in your youth
都是你青春里
The best memories
最美好的回忆
I think
我觉得
It's quite collectible
还挺有收藏价值的
Maybe it will be fine in the future
说不定以后还可以
As the material of my writing
当作我写作的素材
Just tell you whether to give it or not
你就说给不给吧
Give Give Give
给给给
But you have to keep it safe for me
但是你可要帮我保管好
I'm gonna be
我以后可是要成为
Chinese football king's
中国球王的
OK
好啊
Then please help me pack it
那你快帮我打包吧
Good
好
Go ahead
说吧
Why did you call me over
叫我过来什么事啊
This is for you on sunny days
晴天 这个给你
What's wrong
怎么了
You're not the favorite
你不是最喜欢
Is this a taste
这个口味吗
It's really my favorite flavor
确实是我最喜欢的口味
But I just feel strange
但是我就是觉得很奇怪
Why do you buy milk tea every time
为什么你每次买奶茶
Always available
总能买到
My favorite flavor
我最喜欢的味道
And
还有
Why did you suddenly follow me
为什么你会突然跟我
Appear in the same cram school
出现在同一个补习班
These aren't coincidences, are they
这些都不是巧合吧
I know
我知道
You don't even live near my house
你根本就不住我家附近
I also know
我还知道
Every time you take me home
你每次送我回家
It's not a smooth road at all
根本就不顺路
But you still do
可是你还是会
Send me home every time
每次都送我回家
Why on earth is this
这到底是为什么呀
Don't tell me, right
不说是吧
Then there were two juniors just now
那刚才有两个小学弟
Send me two friendship letters
送给我两封交友信
Should I go back and take it apart
我要不要回去拆开看看
No dismantling is allowed
都不准拆
Why
为什么
Clear day
晴天
Don't you really remember me
你真的不记得我吗
Actually, we've known each other a long time ago
其实我们很早就认识了
Still remember Xiaoshengchu
还记得小升初
That summer summer
那年暑假吗
You're in an alley
你在一个巷子里
Helped someone who was thin and didn't pull much
帮助过一个瘦不拉几的
The bullied little boy
被欺负的小男孩
That little boy is me
那个小男孩就是我
You were like a
你当时像一个
Appear like a heroine
女侠一样出现
So cool
太酷了
Get a shout
大喊一声
Scared them all away
把他们都吓跑了
That's because I have a loud voice
那是因为我嗓门大
They're afraid I'll call someone
他们怕我喊人呗
Actually
其实
As soon as I heard your voice
我一听到你的声音
I recognized you
就认出你了
Thank you for that day
感谢你那天
Everything done for me
为我做的一切
So I decided
所以我决定
Whenever you need help
每当你需要帮助的时候
I must be by your side
我一定在你身边
Didn't you tell me earlier
你不早说
So you are
原来你就是
To repay me
为了报答我呀
Then I have a loud voice
那我本来就嗓门大
Have helped more people
帮助过的人多了
How can I remember
我哪记得呀
Actually, a lollipop
其实一根棒棒糖
Something that can be solved
就可以解决的事
This is
这是
This is the lollipop you gave me
这是你给过我的棒棒糖
I saved it all
我都存起来了
What are you doing
你这是
I like you
我喜欢你
Come and see if it looks good
来来来 看好不好看
Do not throw the leakage
不要甩 漏液
Definitely not me and sunny days
肯定没有我和晴天的
That one looks good
那张好看
That's necessary
那必须的
This is good
这个不错
Dear senior high school graduates
各位高三的毕业生
It's about to start
马上就要开始
Taking graduation photos
拍摄毕业照了
Taken graduation photos
拍毕业照了
Then let's go
那走吧
Go, go, go, go, go
走 走 走 走吧 走吧
Good teachers and students
好 各位老师 各位同学
Everyone, look at my camera
大家看我镜头啊
Don't blink when shooting
拍的时候不要眨眼睛啊
Good come
好 来
Come on, everyone, keep your backs straight
来 大家后背挺直啊
One Two Three
一 二 三
Why don't you two show off at all
你俩为什么完全不摆呀
scheming
心机
What are you two doing
你俩干吗呢
The scheming is really
心机 真的是
Have a good one
好好来一个
Come, come, come, start over
来来来 重新来
The ugliest must be the ugliest
最丑的 一定要最丑的
It's okay, you don't have to move, you're ugly
没事 你不用动你都丑
You you you
你 你 你
Come on, come on, come on
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, three, two, one
来来来 三 二 一
And at the end there is one more
最后还有一个
Long live graduation
毕业万岁
It's finally over
终于完了
His face stiffened with laughter
脸都笑僵了
That's the end
就这么结 结束了
It seems that there is something wrong
好像缺点什么
Then do you want to give it to Chen County
那你们想不想给辰郡
Leave some last souvenir
留点最后的纪念
What are you trying to do
你又想搞什么
Squad, follow me
小分队 跟我来
Walk, walk, walk
走 走 走
Go
走
Open the door
开门 开门
Open the door, open the door
开门 开门 开门
Junior brothers and sisters
学弟学妹们
Today we are about to graduate
今天我们即将毕业
But your journey
但是你们的征程
It's just beginning
才刚刚开始
Here it is
在这里
We have a few words
我们有几句话
I want to tell you
想告诉你们
dejected
垂头丧气
It's not our Chenjun style
不是我们辰郡的风格
Flying against the wind can create miracles
逆风飞翔才能创造奇迹
Don't fear failure
不要害怕失败
Don't be afraid to be alone
也不要害怕孤单
Because what you're going through
因为你们现在经历的
There are countless people
都是无数人
Already experienced
已经经历过了的
So it's not a big deal
所以没有什么大不了的
Don't care what others say
别管别人怎么说
It's enough to walk your own way
走好你自己的路就够了
There is no shortcut to success
成功没有捷径
Only by redoubling the effort
只有付出加倍的努力
can be obtained
才可以获得
No matter how tired you are from studying, you have to eat well
学习再累也要好好吃饭
Cherish a section
珍惜一段
A time that will never be repeated
永远都不会重来的时光
Be sure to cherish it
一定要好好珍惜
The people around you
你们身边的人
Youth without regrets
青春无憾
As long as you work hard, you won't regret it
只要努力就不会后悔
Come on, you guys are the best
加油 你们是最棒的
College entrance examination means
高考意味着
The End of High School
高中时代的结束
But my youth
但我的青春
Because I met you guys
因为遇见了你们
To become different
才变得与众不同
Some people don't matter how hard they fall
有的人不管摔得有多重
All have the courage to start over
都有重新开始的勇气
Some people will do it for you
有的人会为了你
Be an enemy of the whole world
和全世界为敌
Some people will share it with you
有的人会跟你分享
All the joys and sorrows
所有的快乐与悲伤
Some people pass you by
有的人与你擦肩而过
All with caution
都带着小心翼翼
Some people will untie it for you
有的人会给你解开
every puzzle
每一道难题
Some people will help you block it
有的人会帮你挡下
All the malice
所有的恶意
I've been meeting
我一直在遇见
Different lovely and kind people
不同的可爱善良的人
And then reluctant to separate from them
又继而不舍与他们分离
I sent out a lot of
我发出了许多
A serious voice
认真的声音
Also got a lot
也得到了许多
A sincere response
真诚的回应
The stories that happened
那些发生过的故事
People I've met
遇到过的人
Will be engraved in
都会刻在
In the hearts of each of us
我们每一个人的心里
Never End
永不完结
Doudou, you want to know too
豆豆 你也想知道
My sister's grades
姐姐的成绩吗
Aren't you curious
你就不好奇吗
Anyway, in a few hours
反正再过几个小时
The results are about to come out
就要出成绩了
Regardless of the outcome
不管结果如何
I will insist
我都会坚持
The path I chose
我自己选择的路
Doesn't make sense to the answer
对答案没有意义
You're the same as before
你还是以前
Is that Xiao Xiaohua
那个肖小画吗
Is better
是更好的
Xiao Xiaohua
肖小画
Hello
喂
Come on down. We're both here
下来吧 我们俩到了
Do you think my apprentice is she
你说我徒弟她是不是
Dare not check the results alone
不敢一个人查成绩
So ask us both to be courageous
所以找咱们俩来壮胆啊
You're not much better, are you
你也没好到哪儿去吧
What's wrong with me
我怎么了
Then what are you shaking
那你抖什么呀
I said
我说
Do you need to be so nervous
用得着这么紧张吗
Can you not be nervous
能不紧张吗
I've grown so big
我长这么大
I've never been so serious
从来就没有这么认真过
I studied for more than a year
学了一年多
If you don't do well in the exam
这要是考不好
All the exams are finished
考都考完了
Whether you are nervous or not, the results are there
紧不紧张成绩都在那儿
Don't think so much
别想那么多了
You just look at other people's small paintings
就是 你看人家小画
What a good attitude
心态多好
You're not looking for both of us
合着你不是找我们俩
Come and check your results with you
来陪你查成绩
That
那
Then why are you looking for us
那你找我们干吗
Three years of high school
高中三年呢
I have a regret
我有一个遗憾
Could have been done
本来是可以完成的
If you want to blame, blame this Lan Jinghui
要怪就怪这个兰靖灰
No sense of responsibility
没有责任心
What does it have to do with me
跟我有什么关系啊
The first day we met
咱们认识的第一天
Didn't you just say you wanted to teach me
你不就说要教我
Do you ride a bicycle
骑自行车吗
I can buy the car now
现在车我可买好了
That's all
就这事
No problem
没问题
In the past two years, Master
这两年师父
I made you deserve your name
我让你叫得实至名归
Go
走
Have you noticed
你们有没有发现
This road looks better than it used to be
这条路比原来更好看了
It's been three years since I've been gone
都走了三年了
You just found out now
你现在才发现啊
How do I feel
我怎么觉得
Nothing has changed at all
一点变化都没有
I used to walk every day
以前每天走
When this road
这条路的时候
Not in a hurry to school
不是赶着上学
Just running home
就是奔着回家
Haven't even looked at this road carefully
都没有仔细看过这条路
High school went by so quickly
高中过得好快啊
From now on, the three of us
以后我们仨
There may be few opportunities
可能就很少有机会
Walking this path together like this
像这样在一起走这条路
Do you remember the first time we
你们还记得我们第一次
When we met over there
在那边相遇的时候吗
I remember, of course I remember
我记得 我当然记得
Right at that intersection
就在那个路口
Fortunately, I called the police that time
那次幸亏是我报了警
Otherwise, this kid might
要不然这小子没准
I got into a fight with the driver
就跟那个司机打起来了
Maybe you'll be dropped out of school
可能还会被退学呢
Do you think I saved you
你说 是不是我救了你
You listen to the apprentice
你听听 徒弟
How bad was this man at the time
这个人当时有多坏
He had clearly seen it
他明明都已经看见
There's a camera there
那儿有摄像头
And the police have been called
而且已经报过警
He doesn't tell us either
他还不告诉我们两个
Let us both stay where we are
让我们俩留在原地
It really is
真的是
If I hadn't influenced you
如果不是我当初感化你
To have what you are now
能有你现在这个
Is it human-like
人模人样吗
What do you mean you influence me
什么叫你感化我
Find out that I saved you
搞清楚 是我救了你
A cold and heartless man like you
像你这么一个冷漠无情
A selfish person
自私的人
If I hadn't been friends with you
如果不是我跟你做朋友
Who's gonna be your friend
谁会跟你做朋友
Then who is in two years
那请问是谁在两年之内
painstakingly
辛辛苦苦地
Put sb. 's academic achievements
把某人的学习成绩
Little by little upgraded
一点一点提升上去了
That's because I've been smart since I was a kid
那是因为我打小就聪明
Talented and intelligent
天资聪慧
All right, all right, all right
好了 好了 好了
Think about it this way
那这样想一想
We were at that time
我们那个时候
It's pretty funny
还挺好笑的
I think the funniest
我觉得最好笑的
It must have been that time
一定是那一次
A Spider-Man fell from the sky
天上掉下个蜘蛛侠
Too funny
太搞笑
You guys look funny
你们看着好笑
I've had a backache for several days
我腰疼了好几天
It really hurts
真的疼
But thinking about it this way
但这么想起来
There is still a regret left in high school
高中还留下一个遗憾
I haven't found it till now
我到现在我都没有找到
The person who exchanged my letter
换我那封信的人
Congratulations
恭喜你
No regrets now
现在没有遗憾了
It's you
是你
Surprised or not surprised or not surprised
惊不惊喜 意不意外
I'm telling you it's impossible
我告诉你 不可能
Because I was
因为我当时
I compared your notes
我就对比过你的笔记
I'll just say you're a big fool
我就说你是大傻子吧
I wrote it with my left hand
我是用左手写的
Do you think you are
你看你 是不是
It turns out that the letter
原来那封信
Really at your place
真的在你那儿
No, no, no, no, no, no, no
不对 不对 不对
Doesn't there be another one
那不还有一个
Someone who admires me
仰慕我的人吗
It's me
是我
You wrote it to me
是你写给我的
I wrote it to Ling Dong
我写给凌冬的
Okay, Xiao Xiaohua
好啊 肖小画
Since the first day of school, you've been
你从开学第一天起就
All right, all right, all right
好了 好了 好了
Didn't you say
你不是说
Will you teach me to ride a bike
要教我学骑自行车吗
This is almost the finale
这都快大结局了
You still don't teach
你还不教
Who told you about the finale
谁告诉你大结局了
There's more in the back. Get in the car
后面还有呢 上车
Come on
来吧
Come and help me
来 扶好了啊
Three, two, one go
三 二 一 走
Go ahead
冲呀
Please keep up the good work
请继续努力
Looking back on this youth
回首这段青春
proud
让人骄傲的
Not one by one
并不是一张张
Letter of admission
录取通知书
But the one who goes all out
而是那一个全力以赴
Self who never gave up
不曾放弃的自己
And those
还有那些
The teenager who accompanied him
陪伴在身边的少年
With the greenest appearance
带着最青涩的模样
Walked through together
一起走过了
The best time
最美好的时光
Got it
知道了
I'm sorry I'm late
不好意思啊 我迟到了
Keep you waiting so long
让你等这么久
It doesn't matter. I just arrived, too
没关系 我也刚到
Do you know how far it is
你知道这儿有多远吗
I changed the subway twice before I got there
我换乘两次地铁才到
Give
给
Thank you
谢谢
I haven't finished
我还没说完呢
You know the subway today
你知道今天地铁
How crowded is it
有多挤吗
My makeup is squeezed out
我妆都挤花了
Look at my acne
你看我这个痘
No, I have to make up my mind quickly
不行 我得赶紧补补
Help me get it
帮我拿一下
Higher
高一点
How about it
怎么样
perfect
完美
What's wrong
怎么了
I'd like to try your cup of milk tea
我想尝尝你那杯奶茶
Let's go
走吧
hair
头发
What's wrong
怎么了
It's stuck to the neck
粘到脖子上去了
Ma Yiming
马一鸣
Ma YimingXu Mengyu
马一鸣 徐梦予
Why are you still late
你们怎么还迟到呢
I'm a junior
我这做学弟的
I'm not even late
我都不迟到
You guys are behind us
你们比我们还晚
Ma Yiming
马一鸣
You are admitted to Chengdu University after repeating your studies for one year
你这复读一年考上蓉大
I have the confidence to speak
说话都有底气了
Of course
那当然
I'm a serious college student now
我正儿八经大学生现在
Summer sunny day
夏晴天
I didn't expect everyone to go to college
没想到都上大学了
You still love to eat so much
你还是那么爱吃
You take care of me
你管我
This is my lifelong pursuit
这是我毕生的追求
Let's go, let's go
走吧 走吧
Let's go in quickly
我们快进去吧
Good
好
Don't go after her
你别跟她追求了
If you pursue it again, you're just like her
你再追求你跟她一样
You roll the horse and cry, you shut up, you
你滚 马一鸣 你闭嘴吧你
You guys are here
你们来啦
Small painting
小画
Awesome!
太棒了
It's all right to hold a solo exhibition
办个人画展了都 对
Where is there
哪有 哪有
Okay, we went over and looked at it
行 我们过去看了啊
OK OK
好好好
Bye bye bye bye
拜拜 拜拜
Bye
拜拜
Xiao Xiaohua
肖小画
Li Ruosi
李若丝
You guys, you guys actually
你们 你们居然
Congratulations, congratulations
恭喜 恭喜啊
Not bad Not bad
不错 挺好
Walk, walk, walk
走走走
We went over to have a look
我们过去看看了
OK OK
好好好
Is it not finished
是不是没完了
Come on, come on, come on
过来 过来 过来
Small painting
小画
Isn't it okay to say a few words
说两句是不是不行
You're insulting me
你在侮辱我
Why are you here
你们怎么才来啊
Xiaohua, congratulations
小画 恭喜你啊
I didn't think you were really here
没想到你真的在这儿
Had an exhibition of paintings
办了画展
Congratulations to you too
也恭喜你啊
A new book has been published
新书出版了
I'm yours now
我现在可是你的
A loyal book fan
忠实书迷
Really
真的吗
Of course
那当然
Our senior sister now
我们学姐那现在
First Young Author
年轻作者第一名
Stop blowing rainbow farts, okay
别吹彩虹屁了好吗
Where are Lan Jinghui and Ling Dong?
兰靖灰和凌冬呢
Both of them
他们俩
Didn't I come with you
没跟你们一块来吗
Haven't they come yet
他们还没来吗
I thought they were all here
我以为他们都到了呢
The little paintings are all ready
小画 都准备好了
It's ready to start
可以开始了
Okay, I'll be right there
好 我马上来
OK
好的
Today is such an important occasion
今天这么重要的场合
Both of them are still late
他俩还迟到
Why don't you wait for Xiaohua
要不别等了 小画
Go ahead
快去吧
Good
好
Help you sort it out
帮你整理一下
Thank you all
谢谢大家
Come over to my exhibition
过来参加我的画展
This exhibition
这次画展
I named it Mustard Seed Time
我起名为芥子时光
To record the history of my life
来记录我人生中
The most important journey
最重要的一段旅程
Whenever I feel confused and confused
每当我感到迷茫 困惑
When you are stagnant
停滞不前的时候
can draw strength from it
都能从中汲取到力量
Because cherish
因为珍惜
So I record it with a paintbrush
所以我用画笔记录下来
The school playground
学校的操场
Sycamore trees along a tree-lined road
林荫路旁的梧桐树
Endless homework
写不完的作业
And a smiling face that I can't get tired of watching
和看不腻的笑脸
And
还有
A boy in white riding a bicycle
骑着自行车的白衣少年
Thank you for this journey
感谢这段旅程中
Those people who walked with me
陪我走过的那些人
It is precisely because of them
正是因为有了他们
That's what makes me this little time
才让我这段微小的时光
Emitting an eternal glimmer of light
散发出经久不灭的微光
Good
好
Awesome!
太棒了
Just two days ago, my country's first batch
就在两天前我国第一批
Manned spacecraft Tianwen-7
载人航天飞船天问七号
Successfully landed on Mars
成功登陆火星
This successful landing
这次成功登陆
For my country's aerospace history
对于我国航天史
Has great historical significance
具有重大历史意义
Let's connect
下面让我们来连线
Two astronauts
两位宇航员
Hello everyone
大家好
I'm Astronaut No. 1 Lan Jinghui
我是一号宇航员兰靖灰
I'm Astronaut No. 2 Ling Dong
我是二号宇航员凌冬
What about now
现在呢
It's Beijing time on Earth
是地球北京时间的
Three fifteen o'clock
三点十五分
We offer to our fellow citizens on earth
我们向地球上的同胞
Send a greeting
发出问候
Hello everyone
大家好
Today is our high school classmates
今天是我们高中同学
Xiao Xiaohua's painting exhibition
肖小画的画展
Unfortunately
很遗憾
We can't get to the scene in person
我们不能亲自赶到现场
But it's okay
但是没关系
We're in space
我们在太空
Send her a greeting
向她发出问候
I wish her every success
祝她圆满成功
The exhibition was a complete success
画展圆满成功
You can see
各位可以看到
Where are we now
我们现在呢
In the boundless universe
正在无边无际的宇宙中
Make an interstellar travel
进行星际旅行
The landscape in front of us
眼前的风景
It's really beautiful
确实很优美
Very beautiful
非常优美
People can't help but sigh again and again
让人不禁一次次感叹
The uncanny workmanship of nature
大自然的鬼斧神工
and human
和人类
Smallness in the vast universe
在浩瀚宇宙当中的渺小
Small indeed
确实渺小
Very small
非常渺小
Is that the word I just did
我刚刚是这词吗
Did we say something wrong
咱俩是不是说错了
Did I steal your word
我抢了你词吗
It's not that I remember what you said
不是 我记得你那句话
That's what I said
是我说的来着
Give me a look at the manuscript
稿子 给我看一眼
Script Take a look at the script
剧本 看一眼剧本啊
I'm
我这场是
Here
这儿
Yes indeed
对 确实
Look, go from here
你看 从这儿走
You said it was indeed small
你说确实是渺小
I should say one more thing
我应该再多说一句
Is it not
是不是
Lan Jing Hui Ling Dong
兰靖灰 凌冬
You two come out of here
你俩给我出来
Here it is
在这呢
May I ask you two at my exhibition
请问你俩在我的画展上
What the hell is it
搞什么呢
Not the two of us
不是我俩
It was his idea
这是他的主意
He thinks your exhibition
他觉得你的画展
Should have some cosmic vibe
应该有一些宇宙氛围
This isn't to give you
这不是为了给你
Are you preparing a little surprise
准备一点惊喜吗
You call this a surprise
你管这叫惊喜
Apprentice, do you feel
徒弟 你有没有觉得
After watching this video
看完这个视频之后
The entire exhibition
整个画展
Become a little more high-end
变得高端了些许
And the style
而且格调
It came up at once
一下子就上来了
Then you tell me
那你告诉我
Where is it high-end
它高端在哪儿
Where is the style upgrade
格调升在哪儿
This is human
这可是人类
From interstellar travel
从星际旅行当中
Congratulatory message sent back
发回来的贺电
The only one in the world
全球独一份
Then I'll send you two back now
那我现在把你俩送回去
Is it too late
还来得及吗
Ling Dong, you actually
凌冬你居然
And fooling around with him
也跟他一起瞎胡闹